Ugh, is this even the right way?
It definitely is.
Are you sure?
Stop!
Pick up the pace!
Tell that to the others!
Hey now, don't push!
I remembered this all.
This is where we fought the Red Dragon.
I see.
So you came all the way out here on your last expedition?
Yeah.
This was thought to be the deepest part of the dungeon for a while.
But recently, someone found a door around here that seems to lead farther in.
There were patterns engraved on it, so it was thought to open with magic.
The Island Lord asked us to come copy the patterns for him, but then...
You ran into the Red Dragon and eventually had to retreat.
Alright, let's test our luck.
I think we were around there last time.
Hey!
Found our stuff!
Huh?
It's been ransacked.
Oh no!
Heck yeah!
I found my sleeping bag!
Thank God!
My underwear survived!
You checked for that stuff first instead of money, huh?
It seems like all the food we had was taken.
But everything else is here.
Safe to assume monsters did this.
This is great!
Now I'll be all warm when I fall off!
That's bad.
Let's find a place where we can rest for a bit.
Gives me time to sort my things.
I wonder if the snow makes the cleaners slow down at all.
Something nibbled on my soul!
Hey you!
Remove whatever you just put in your pocket.
Hey Marcel, catch!
Huh?
You're not really well trained for a beast man.
I'm starting to realize where they'd probably put that collar on you.
You're one of those half-foots, I'm assuming.
I'd only just heard of them since there aren't any in the East.
I'd never seen one till coming here.
The name of your race is pretty strange.
I heard it came from your kind getting one of their legs chopped off due to committing too much thievery.
Come on you two, there's no need for that.
Marcel!
Come here!
Oh, you found fish!
Is there a way for us to cut out this uncovered part right here?
I could maybe do it with a magic circle.
That's right!
Do you want to give it a try?
I can teach you how to draw one if you do.
How's your mana sickness been lately?
I haven't been staggering as much.
The hallucinations have gotten a lot worse though.
I caught this fish a lot on the fourth floor.
Is the water flowing in from the upper floors freezing once it gets down here?
Seems a lot of stuff got washed up in this place.
And that completes the circle.
How are you feeling?
A bit tired honestly.
Well, let me activate it then.
All you've got to do is...
Imagine water filling these symbols and...
What's this?
The floor's moving!
A monster!
There?
That thing is an ice golem.
Hmm...
I see.
Above you!
Look out!
My house!
There's a fish!
There's too much crap in it!
Hey, uh...
How do I kill this big snowman?
It's a golem, so you're gonna have to destroy its core!
Core?
Where would that even...
Well?
Where is it?
Give me a sec!
Is that it?
No, that's a fish.
Yeah, there's too much crap in it!
Hey!
Try to distract the enemy to buy me time!
I still need to find the car!
Huh?!
That bastard.
How do I know he's not lying?
This better not be a trick or something.
The snow!
Why'd it stop moving?
Look!
Can you hurry?
How long do I have to keep this up?
You're good!
That was long enough!
Yes!
Nailed it!
Idiot!
Do you think this is a game?
You're the idiots!
Check out!
We're the hero idiots!
By the way!
While I am able to use ranged weapons,
I can't exactly do that much damage with any of them!
So you better not go counting on me in a fight!
The rest is up to you!
Fine.
As long as I know how to kill it.
It looks like I'm the only one in the group who's agile enough to take on an enemy that big!
Can't believe how slow you guys are!
I...
I....
Are all of you doing ok?
It'll start to warm up soon!
Okay, it'll start to warm up soon. That magic circle will get hot, so please be careful not to burn yourselves.
Take off all your wet clothes so we can dry them. That means you too. Here, I'll hold this up to cover you.
Do you need help with yours, Laios?
Could one of you guys help him out?
You really don't have to do that, you know.
No, it's not that big of a deal.
Not like anyone's gonna get excited over a beast getting naked.
What the hell are you doing?
Well, it would be bad if you felt colder.
At least tell me the number of nipples and where the tail connection is...
It's finally gotten warmer in here. I'll start fixing up a hot meal for everyone.
But first, I need to thaw this.
Might as well melt it with the magic circle.
Must have been too close.
Wow, but this is actually nice. It's like a sauna.
We haven't been able to take a bath for a while, so let's sweat it out a little bit.
Wait, that comes off?
Why is it only me?
Gut the fish and then make a broth from the head and bones.
I feel like we're gonna smell like fish after this.
Finally, slice a couple mushrooms and nightmares.
Lightly boil the shapeshifter meat and remove any scum that forms.
Beat some harpy eggs and then add that mixture to the broth along with all the other ingredients.
Pour all that into cups.
Place the cups into the pan with ice golem fragments and put over a fire.
Look, I made this from her fur.
Bored much?
Lastly, place some mandrake leaves over the top and...
It's red...
Hey!
Don't just start eating on your own.
You've gotta wait until everyone gathers at the table.
Why should I wait?
I defeated that thing all by myself!
I think I deserve to eat before the rest of you!
A meal's something you only start when everyone's together.
Chill, Chuck.
Lios is outside.
Mind calling him back in?
Sure thing.
Oh, this feels great.
Is this guy for real?
Now that everyone's gathered, I think it's that time.
So let's eat!
Let's read it in!
It's pudding.
Oops!
Sorry, Marcel.
Delicious!
What a waste of time.
Hey, Yuzutsumi.
What is it?
This is for you.
I sewed up one of the bags that got ripped.
You should use it.
And, uh, I'm sorry I called you a beast before.
I have a notoriously foul mouth.
You know, traveling with a group of strangers can be uncomfortable.
But once you get used to it, you'll see the advantages.
You can rely on them to handle things for you.
Um...
Uh...
Thank you for the good meal!
Thanks.
Come on, are you done yet?
Almost.
Just a second.
This goes here, and...
Done!
Ta-da!
Their Namaari's close, but they're perfect, right?
It's hard to move.
It did take a while to take them in, though.
Yeah, now I'm cold again.
Look, I'm sorry.
Let's start heading out now.
Hold on.
Great.
I boiled the mandrakes in some sweet sauce.
Figured it'd be a good thing to snack on while we walked.
Hey.
Here.
But this belongs to you.
Don't want it.
Why?
It's really good.
I said I don't want the thing!
Oh, come on.
Just try a little bite.
Here.
Cut it now!
Oh, horrible.
We've been walking for two seconds, and there's already blood drawn.
Hey, just leave her be.
She'll eat when she gets hungry.
So why don't you want to eat it?
It's a monster.
Everyone says that.
But how is it different than eating an animal?
If you eat monsters, you'll get a weird disease and then transform into one.
So no thank you!
Things would be so much easier if that was something that actually happened.
Monsters are believed to be unclean, and it's obviously not entirely logical, but that's
the reason most people, including me, find it gross.
You just get this feeling that you'll absorb something bad.
New diseases spring up from creatures coming in contact with humans all the time, so it's
not fair to question why someone doesn't feel like eating monsters.
Mmm!
This is really tasty!
By the way, when you had to eat food you didn't like...
How did you go about handling that exactly?
What did I do?
Ugh.
Here, Tade, you can have this.
Thanks, Isu!
Me nice to be!
That never happened.
There's no way!
Come on, you two!
Let's go!
This storm probably won't die down any time soon.
Then let's set up camp around this area.
I'm getting hungry.
But Senshi fell asleep.
We can prep a meal in the meantime.
What ingredients do we have left?
There's nightmares and a mandrake, eggs and some mushrooms, whatever this is.
Got any fish?
Nope.
We're all out of that.
Rice, then?
We're actually pretty low on rice as well.
Don't you have anything better than this gross stuff?
This is everything.
Liar!
You're hiding it from me.
You can't be a picky eater when you're inside a dungeon.
So you should get used to trying things.
No!
I only eat the things I want to eat!
Please just listen.
Eating monsters isn't going to turn you into one.
Do people who eat pigs and sheep turn into either of those animals?
If someone who was blind ate an eyeball, would they regain their sight?
Sheep only eat plants, but they stay sheep, don't they?
Food and nutrition are more complex than you might think they are.
That's why people are still conducting research.
I'm sick of all your lies!
How in the hell do you explain that, then?
Explain what?
A tree actually grew a sheep.
That's a baromets.
But to think it would actually show up at a time like this...
So, first of all, that kind of plant is always like...
Shut it!
I'm sick of all your yammering!
Whatever, man.
I'm gonna go catch that sheep.
What's a baromets?
A monster?
That's what it's classified as, but it's harmless.
However, what's not harmless is they attract carnivores.
Careful, Izutsumi!
I don't need your warnings.
And we shouldn't linger.
Let's harvest it and then...
Quiet.
Huh?
Crap!
A direwolf pack!
I need a staff!
Hey, hold it!
Where are you going?
I'm not a fan of dogs.
They're annoying and they smell bad.
That's your reasoning for coming in here all on your own?
I'm relying on them.
Depending on your party members to pick up your slack is your idea of teamwork, isn't it?
Uh, no, that's...
That's not what that means at all!
What do you mean?
You didn't fight when we were dealing with that ice golem earlier.
It's true I relied on you guys back then, but it wasn't because I didn't want to help out.
Uh, hey, why don't we go back?
No thanks.
I smell fire on the wind.
If we follow it, we'll get back to where we came from.
Hey, wait up!
The path to the right smells like the campfire, but it looks rough, so left it is.
Do you know where you're going?
Is this the right direction?
I take whatever path I like the best.
You should learn to do that, too.
Why bother doing things you don't want to do?
You eat monsters, even though you don't really want to eat them.
It doesn't make any sense.
Well, I mean...
I think the wolves are coming after us.
Should we try to fight them?
I'm typically able to use explosive magic, but I don't have my staff right now.
It's too cramped in here anyway, so I could stun them with a really bright light, maybe.
Let's just lose them!
Whoaaaa!
Howie!
Hey! Get back here, Asebi!
Fess up. You made Tade shovel snow for you, didn't you?
Nope.
Don't lie to me! She fell off the training hall roof because of that!
Unlike you, Tade is incredibly clumsy.
So don't shove jobs you don't like onto her.
Show some gratitude for us taking you in.
Nah.
Hey, Tade.
Why'd you do something I never asked you for?
You're such an idiot.
But Tade just...
What was it that Tade said to me back then?
It doesn't matter.
I messed up.
The blast changed the wind's direction, so I missed this one.
Cl-close your eyes.
Close your eyes.
Do it!
Now!
I can't...
I... I can't...
I... I...
Is it Tade?
Are you alive?
Oh...
Your arm is broken. Can you move? Let's go and find the others.
Listen. You wanted to know why I eat monsters, didn't you?
I've been thinking about it, and I have multiple goals that I want to accomplish.
Like rescuing my best friend and learning everything I can about magic.
So, while working to achieve all my goals, I sometimes run into things that I don't like.
Something bothersome, or tiring, or having to eat something I really don't want to.
None of those things are bad on their own, but...
If I continued avoiding them, I'd keep getting further and further away from my path, right?
Exactly like we're doing in this cave.
I'm curious. Why did you decide to come along with us?
Are you stupid? Because you told me I needed to find that mad whatever guy to even have a chance to break this curse!
Now follow me!
Exactly. And that means we probably won't be able to take the easy path there.
Izutsumi! Marcil! You're both okay!
You guys are okay too, right?
Not really, but at least we're all in one piece.
We have Laios' intimidation skills to thank for that.
It helps that most of the wolves went after you, Marcil.
You hurt?
I think her arm is broken.
Would you be able to help me out while I'm casting a healing spell on it, Laios?
You did great, Izutsumi!
The healing spell hurt more than breaking it.
I was planning on harvesting the baromets, but all the ripe ones were taken by the dire wolves.
This was the only one left for grabs, but it's not ready yet.
Let's see if we can cook it.
There's a little sheep inside the vegetable.
I can't!
For a completely different ethical reason, I refuse!
First, cut up the baromets' ribs into whatever portions you want.
Season them and put them on the fire.
After both sides of each have been nicely browned,
add wine over top, cover the pan, and then braise them.
Next, boil the remainder of the fruit, peel off the skin, and cut it into chunks.
Add some garlic and simmer all of it together.
With the sauce finished, you take that, pour it over the meat, and...
It's ready!
This helping's yours, Catgirl.
Go on, take it.
What's all the weird-looking stuff?
It's the skin of the baromets, fruit, and a handful of sprouts.
You could have just fried the meat and been done with it.
The baromets.
It may resemble an everyday sheep,
but it tastes more like crab!
That doesn't make it better!
This is so good.
I didn't know something this delicious could exist.
Wait, that reminds me.
Tade, why'd you do something that I never asked you for?
You're such an idiot.
Tade just wants...
to be as accommodating as she can to everyone.
Because this place is amazing!
Three meals a day,
a bath to keep clean,
and a cozy photon!
I definitely cannot get myself kicked out of here!
I will do even the smallest chore to show I'm useful!
Hey, Asabi.
Don't get discouraged just because of some minor inconveniences.
Oh, and if I do good,
Lady Miser will give me treats sometimes!
So that's what you're really after, huh?
Guess this is what she meant.
Sometimes you get tasty things out of doing what you don't wanna.
Good job!
I'm proud of you, Izutsumi!
You did so well today!
Way to go, bud!
Turn it out, you bastards!
What do you think you're doing?!
Don't touch me!
I only ate it because I had no other choice!
You'll never see me eat gross veggies or monsters again!
You won't know if they're gross or not till you try them, though.
By the way, Marcel,
you've barely touched your food.
After all the lecturing you gave me earlier,
don't you even try to get out of eating.
Marcel deeply regretted being the one to close off her own escape route.
Ah, dungeon food.
Delicious in dungeon.